{
  "LANGHINDI": 18,
  "qu1": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tA file is organized so that the ordering of data record is same as or close to the ordering of data block in some index. Then that index is called</p>",
      "OPT1": "Dense",
      "OPT2": "Sparse",
      "OPT3": "Clustered",
      "OPT4": "Unclustered",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18439070",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "Data Science and artificial Intelligence",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu2": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tFind the highest normal form of the relation <em>R</em>(<em>A</em>, <em>B</em>, <em>C</em>, <em>D</em>) that holds following FDs.</p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAQUAAAAUCAYAAACEaygbAAAIfklEQVR4Xu1ae0xTVxj/uRljiDEuOEVdNHFBRJ1zRaZRM5liNh8Itg4H6kAEpsCAoogTK2jViS9EwDcI4mM+qDx86wxbdNGxNXE6lbHp1KHdYqJxzbIY0+0+TqG1t7fn9l7qYm7/hHO/c77f+b7f9zhfh3+ZH9SfioCKgIoAQaCDSgqqLagIqAg4IqCSgmoPKgIqAk4IyCAFG6zmUszQNiP50kZEBnT0MbTPYKnJwpjMetd9/cKRUWlEamgAXqE61e+oTZyKBeceuaz2C89B+coEDA/oRCVJ/iIRvTjhfgialY3sOC3CArvK287aiE0fpeP6p4exI+oNebJkf/0UFvM5nDZth3Hvj23SgmfCkBMHXVgguoju4Z092CxmnDhlwtb8fWhqlT8UMfl6fDL9PQR2obMg2eo7CXixvuU9KXAGFY+SG/2QZjqETI34lSkLmoO0Jw0wjJyDk0nVuKTXoKO1CbVrFmGBaRh2XcpDWFfaS7XhScNyjIlvRAKnjx+szXUoSM9FbUgpLqwMg0wXlAYBp1cesKUaxrDu5NsnaG4wYU/BOhy4MZDBvYw5ZzdpcltXP4a5cC6ii8zolkGw81KS7M+4OzPiuP90zIuZBA0hYLvDlv0Sjkpa/KntgcGyZgMWHeuG+JQYRGhIALFZYD5+Akd3tWB8Va4E+5GNQpuAF+xbXpICa1DzYXgaAs2Xu3Etw4Tq+CDKqKwgeKwoSw2SR64ANtW1Rrtn5kKM1N6GQVIGY480wIbW76yMntGI/ikZF3ZFIUDho4uK4/Q6gtFndyEusLNzHLlfg7RwPc6MKvTyXCQS5T7EhJBvUXJ1Jk4ejUcgLX8qiYPtLmpTZ2PHgPU4qA91zQYs9cg/NQDLaO2Lyh6e4n5NDj7c3h8Vh1OhcckGmMwx7xsMyot9AZi8eN/yihRszRXQpf8Fw+FI3MuMgiFgo0KR9ClaTIuQcCsW1Qvf9ZAu8pbJE8BZzGrNVv5Bc0UidJen41RpFHpTGzohgD0TcKhRDw1bDdmaUDktGZfnVKEkqq8M0vNSr7nADvtZnBzxIRqW6pB4PKrtrFIcldMrH4/yivHx3RUYs+Q1iVmV+81sLSYkJdxBSnUGQjym3iQ7K+juxjmlKCXBHrhsohj+e+VkWmJnk37fdmnt51v0WEonBY7Z83A7qZBJXTtzDjjxaLhykcZ6DeWpn+FiZAV2avt5cMTnonuPhzDv24ptTe8ge/FUifUg6StgGRd9e1gasb+kCk3DU5ETFURFUKKwe6PXsXFuMgEBAqO+czZK5iL1djSqmMjsxxL8hHOIEshIqEU6LXyCm+V6TLk4GV/v1KKPKCnz5LbQv5Av/bzb0OErGnsgRKTvhgpBwpV9CF6ApPsme7a3b1GqJpEUnA2qC+x1+CMYJaXq4qfjok1oOYLr92JhiFjNzGcFE/MvEoFsE24BkkcMw4jJGgRQZwn2rEAL45W/iSy22RSHEUNHYZK93qQE1d0yqXrFPMpy4ywkU7jK9FIkpv02tvSYfw+J+0jazEXNLPyxuq38kqkmk2HdgSlJh+LgLagXy/iembEpNBHX85Tam8YefFcS0t83i7hvfIvmbiWRAmdQbC1r95vWHYIVbjYyNe8PRYiIuIbZ5wuRMNBdi484h0VPIirznbfNQRfn4BtRmZkN0FQ4NvtoYHVLC5R6sVnLTByfsk/4VYA002q1u6WVbVwkmoEFJy0uB1S82Wj9DusjUnB1dgVKE4YIZ1qKkwKNPfiOFBh2pLxvZqXPfMuz/dKTAmdQ83D6g23O9TVnoKm4tkik2fjAhLjeOuzxfB7XFb1SUd24Edo+Ak+CXG2sRXFYlUNEJdGiKERSvc3VchMOYazjS4qgfIcjtpdenLMsBcqEXnVIk2wJYDxXgMjetE+l/HdTT49FnVOvhSbruAdT3PvQ7fnVixscgoTqY8KlIMF3w1sKve5Q2QOxj7VvSu+jtNd9y/EtL27E0yeUpCDWreVrceWajXwq9eD8F4iddVc8UxDoNAO8kadjuYQoKvTywBxD8FnQE6Ri/6fTiycoM+IFSjI+ohQAqw9Kan7y31VhgEtzjeiuYLORRcD24CyWxn6OFrFMAeRZdGdfbJBEcG4wprIH+wzAfvTbJA1D6TdPc9++9i3PWlCRgrghknTszEQcEnze8XwI5xVs5zYLobrfkPW9WE/h+bkCdk6CpPzbOyF7dzbCWt+72abhGhzwXyz87EWIxKmbz72dL8GOV1NQljdeWn9CUGVaveyZQFdsdpyzYN/P6w5g25IG9Fy99rnmJzv4cwSlufXwX7XVdXaBlA0G5Ai+yPAvOBeYFxxluvF8LZ2GW1k14j0FljwsX2HFnHTsxbTnhpRYnc7j8l0/DAofg0C/P5kmcgkM+3vCKGhn9PbA5OpoWD4fiZVwGVLiZiMutaDL4LEyh8Po7tu3vkXnix5JgTeYzQynk1+4w9s4l+bqUNI6CCi3t0CYdfwR9HeXcpJjuJyL+7vQJJo9XXzdTTQipFZ0wxkx6kk6GqDl6mXXbQ7Gjx7naqz2NLz3Klend7mjCNc5DAfd5fYW+AwhDhX9S9Do8fWBYGdtRsORSqxzmSpsa/QyHWUme9qOXm6iO7092O/LcRDM3iST0ah2MgO6+/atb9HYKb/GIynQi1Jmpe3nSiTVBaOIck7B466KzRp43El0geJ6OezGlRuRVxCvRAouT00m9N9EedIZvF2URjGnQLuZt7MntPKVX9ee9638aZ0l/u9IQVmF2VR8BVY+jsHa+MHyZw2UPZwy0tjSIKMYj9MMiAvy6SC2MuenkMKm2HqjFSnrYhHkcSCKQqC6RBSBl5wU1NtXEVARkIqASgpSEVPXqwi85AiopPCSX7CqnoqAVARUUpCKmLpeReAlR+A/YQNpECgSo9wAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\" /></p>",
      "OPT1": "1NF",
      "OPT2": "2NF",
      "OPT3": "3NF",
      "OPT4": "All of these",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Dsdj/LJX8pBs6q+b96fwiQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Dsdj/LJX8pBs6q+b96fwiQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18439070",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "Data Science and artificial Intelligence",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu3": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tConsider the following about OLAP:<br />\r\n\t<em>S</em><sub>1</sub> : Roll-up operation aggregates data to a higher level of details.<br />\r\n\t<em>S</em><sub>2</sub> : Roll up operation performed by dimension reduction, dimension are not removed from cube.<br />\r\n\tWhich of the above is/are correct?</p>",
      "OPT1": "<p>\r\n\tOnly <em>S</em><sub>1</sub></p>",
      "OPT2": "<p>\r\n\tOnly <em>S</em><sub>1</sub> and <em>S</em><sub>2</sub></p>",
      "OPT3": "<p>\r\n\tOnly <em>S</em><sub>2</sub></p>",
      "OPT4": "None of these",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Dsdj/LJX8pBs6q+b96fwiQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Dsdj/LJX8pBs6q+b96fwiQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18439070",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "Data Science and artificial Intelligence",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu4": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tConsider a dataset with income value as an attribute in dollar format:<br />\r\n\t$ 100000, $ 120000, $ 140000, $ 160000, $ 180000, $ 200000, $ 220000 and $ 240000<br />\r\n\tWhat is the Z-score normalized value of $ 180000, if the mean of data is $ 170000 and the standard deviation is $ 40000 (upto 2 decimal places)</p>",
      "OPT1": "0.25 [0.24 - 0.26]",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "hfjo/9q4EeRPx0BfLYz1eelbaa3HzVK52aqj8fFQMKg=",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "5kxMa8YwwyHwJY15nzG3sQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18439070",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "Data Science and artificial Intelligence",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu5": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tConsider a block of size such that it can hold:<br />\r\n\t\u2022 either 5 records of a relation <em>R</em>, or<br />\r\n\t\u2022 be used as a B<sup>+</sup> tree internal node with degree 11, or<br />\r\n\t\u2022 B<sup>+</sup> tree leaf node with degree 10.<br />\r\n\tIf R has 1000 records, then the smallest number of blocks that could be used to store <em>R</em> and a sparse B<sup>+</sup> tree index on key of R is ________.</p>",
      "OPT1": "223",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "oqiuqUPFSPobsw7WP5tdfA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "5kxMa8YwwyHwJY15nzG3sQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18439070",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "Data Science and artificial Intelligence",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu6": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tWhich of the following statements is/are correct?<br />\r\n\t<em>S</em><sub>1</sub> : Some OLAP multi-dimensional database modeling tools are optimized for snowflake schema.<br />\r\n\t<em>S</em><sub>2</sub> : In snowflake schema data is not redundant as dimensions are normalized.</p>",
      "OPT1": "<p>\r\n\tOnly <em>S</em><sub>1</sub></p>",
      "OPT2": "<p>\r\n\tOnly <em>S</em><sub>2</sub></p>",
      "OPT3": "<p>\r\n\tBoth <em>S</em><sub>1</sub> and <em>S</em><sub>2</sub></p>",
      "OPT4": "None of these",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18439070",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "Data Science and artificial Intelligence",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu7": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tA block can hold either 5 records or 6 keys pointers. A database contain n records, then how many blocks are needed to hold the data file and dense index?</p>",
      "OPT1": "<p>\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAFAAAAAsCAYAAADy8T8XAAAE3klEQVRoQ+2af0jcZRzHX8r6tc2xaNFuUhELPaLY4pYlQboTZYJzcrJG/qy7asJETfRm8xrVnfkT3doNRstjntKPxR3WLIfiqcEImoKxRadowWLewgjmhMUaV9/v937onG13913stO/zpzwfv5/n9byf5/O5z+eJ+VsYKCNiAjEKwIjZSYYKQHn8QgA4N4Hr9Fd0lE2ya9SKTrXK/8lZJvrbqSuuxO4R/5SB8YSZisIkVLEyvVpG5v+iwGt4RvvoPXkE06WneeXCp7SOv8qA24J2nY+Od8JGdt1VDja8QdIjM7hMetLqp9E7ejiue5z/C8NbABzkp7hktAmXcRZvJ/dMCSPuKjSSAK/jcdZyaH01jdoNQaCZiQammkdwV2kI6HQZiSkiV0O4A39dAuDN3xIVmZnoJH2kiyrN6qCCDU1P4JgWjn7cz7hOtmM2OHjMMUiH7tGIHI42ozsDcO48tn3vM1nchkUbT+z1UdpKfyA5Yxyd8WG6B7fQY50iq/QZvt1ezsxHp4PKjTYg4fojD6DXjS1Ti6FPiiKLAol4zEvRfLmGwo1bee2dfNRXuine1McuUZHBYBSuy9E1Xx7AhWuZc+M0l5PbdI6Mdhe9+g0M7d9BWucLOM62ootfxazLhLrxSYZ69SSskChz5wD6I3MwkFSuwZ6Zxed7egSYaiEq/8mErYjU8RLcjVrWRZeQIvYmQoC/4zrwMdQYg2mNFJtHW1BvG6JEDCSbXMJx/YyUcTv6hPuFvEc87rsZ3vvNigkg4ppvDzBwz51bmAf61TScQreYB6ruxes5w+EaE2MpRziqfwqveFwLoCuQO8662K8286C1mvv6fuEl6z5/ShTx5keF4S0A+tMX+9SNjm5ulvLBZ2f6MeUVUz/kCyCqomasZfnkaFTCcRUUKt5/lw4w3aFDJU7wOAVFlnLB+B4VL2exU5q3/MftFbj81/ifrkABKBOvAlABKJOATHNFgQpAmQRkmi+pwJiYGJn/NnTz5d6SUY5w6Hu95EwFoAJQJgGZ5ooCFYAyCcg0D0OBXuYm+jlWV0W1/bxYPiDV2EhLxR40QjXGNxa1OlVFNHfUUpKewFqZjkareegAxbJWdjOXD1ooT3qI31z15KW9y7jewdnjOuJjr3HRWclzpVexuNqEGuAVf6vzHpqlRtP6aGUgy6/QAQrlKMOh9bQFqsmBOuFUpa/dGevrj5i2ds1XnKUaYBqdhQMrqgq9kHjoABfvkwQwi870TzhVlcRqqa1pAqkfIpbwhbEY8gpsFkcIcBa3zUj5ZC4nLOnSUw5fOf8YL97Q8w2tpyzrDN1l4zAB+kr5iYYv/G7PB5It0x8qAMPbTCHiOhvYm1vPUEY7P5r/IPt5RYHhMVxwx33XBQXJrWxe6g7caJ3vjYT3haifHeIR9gpN8SYaeJ0P/I+JpJUJTzha1Dv5uqSbU2/OYV4ccaUoXMCYZUFgiXok4TkYIkDfc7bM1GF2dDcIeaDQUfN6+P5wDXljWnqOFqJeO8toSwHbqv/i7QGb8EYmTrgv30JregCr9DIhkGyH52C0zw4ZIN6L/sS4z7cm8VeGtYz8HM38g0o/1JxKO2KzU1XUSketgfSElfIO4ebtDB1gtEvhLvmnAJQJXgGoAJRJQKa5okAFoEwCMs0VBcoE+A/Gq6Kbd3EdrwAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\" /></p>",
      "OPT2": "<p>\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAEEAAAAoCAYAAAChDJfXAAAELElEQVRoQ+2Za2hbZRjHfy1FB65DweFi0SGTLEjFQUZdv6wupcVBa0eKypxtNGGusNCO0WRzjcJM6+yFbrJU1NlqY/FSaOi2YktK0q7QLy4BpQOT0CpWaAoVYTWgSImeS9OlF2gybXNcz/spCSc57/vL/7mc/5P1t7DY4itLhQCpQ4hF8A9do7t2koqgC6MmJ0k/cWKRMYaufUrtRAXBbiOa/5G61oHwF9Ggl8Heyzhm8zk6/SXt4dfwhRox7MiGeJTg9QF6L33EbMEBpls6CNt9hJoN7Li3IIzwQ24hBu1tPKZDVI7XEAjVoxeFIEEIk1t8EO3v/ZgerWS8NUCoXk+yTpTOI/Vw4JfVEJJPF/WsAeGOkiwtT9A3I4RR7o/4eztxWvp4vG+EbuNjGWe0sRAWgly0fk9haRijfSf9I88w4JqizPo0Y4fqmPt4iGbDw/c4BOl4C0Q9VvRXH6Bq1z5ef+sYOil0vFSIyliWYDPDY2OVIJ3pV/xnnqf48wP03WzHmJfDvN+BrvlJRgfNaIX8mum18RDiIboOl/H1ywMMmnVk8yeRrmqeC9copopsPAQpYX5FUdiNWbtNqCgilBe5ceIbRSRFUYWpQ5A2b8AykdQnJLdLkS4O77UwsaxPiMvSfxV6Er3FvJ8zOicPuWzc7/2Jg66TcrnN4EoBwmJpdE8t3+aeVrlfmJNLo3vFIfZI/cJuxsR8MHuOmUQXKSnDyrT9PKdeKqNcrxFCJLMrBQiZ3eBm3F2FkFZO2Iy/JEP3UJWgKkGWnqqE9SBkZWVtSpRm2uFTlbCeEjZFBgq4iaoEVQlqdVgKxLsIh3kiw500mU7jjoq/U4r9MyenqgrQJJ6EBHt++MMmTDY34iWa6na6GyyUaJXpQacNIS48Mr/Q9Advv3ecgkfm8DvMFF+Ywdw3wBXjbrLjP+M5XoZ1oR5/R5XgQvtwvGLiAjYC1+vQb8/0M+PqTJwmBNEvbODSg7Ylg1SEIvoIU4tWe7b0/gP2+RIm6qKnUOylaukzBZSEpC2kCWH15mUIHkoCPdTrt0nWmcCEzoSTJHxlJagMeyirDvHvIMRu0XXyHSZNF2k05AnmSIxgWzn7bXvlGUPCSV5zJqEcNdwdhITV5pUyY1JyfIqZ9q0CIflPjIXwOOuobJmgtPMqzt/sPLsllLBCyXdi3kcPTgptO9fICe+ySyFjt5WBmGY4CIOUc5/AWbs8lV5cC8E2dPtHqQm4eeO28HpZJUhUh0kak5KlcjJC2n7C4uDkRhH9Yp+guU8YTI/z/lkH3xVdpsOcz/bYt7SVHxG6ghP4vngTQ25ESJ5HceSc5+YVI3nKaxPSN1Xi0WG5+RmVk6KmuhVX7TGOJFnnMpgaTrtvCVfkU93aRkNNCVoFNkriGdIMByWJ+L/biwpBVYKsJlUJAoR/AFeWh6ct18ASAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\" /></p>",
      "OPT3": "<p>\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACkAAAA1CAYAAADcdMIWAAACqklEQVRoQ+2YXUiTURjHfxtRXYgVFDUiuwjcLrpy3YiRNm+20D5eIcLS1QZ5YaSBqYlCYX5LFhgZ4vCjmz5mxgwjYWl3mQbebaOLKHCEESheRBerd2NCEHubcTjz4pzLMZ7z5/d/nvf8zzH90hebfJmUSEEOKZKCQJKSZCy6QGDqCXe9fnL8bxjRdhAJPmOotZnunH6WRjQsolT8o04KkWss9LWzmJ9HWLvPnokH5E2OslhykYK3VZxebiHU5SA7syKTu0fHcdv97Ks4hPVSHR7bCuPuM7w49Vwne0CSRFLbDTFWg83YigO4/JMMagcxrwZpsA1gnRnFk7t9M4j8QcRXifWxk/CUh1yzLjviw1X0kYbQbRzZ+g+SlsEn6Itu7QkeFj5lymPDTFL07DmpQxPnkFpkwtp6ePSKLsdu/a/fCDY4ubyriZFt75g71sI1e5YUlilErvfjd/qX+tEsW3QxcbLHKftcxlDtWVyldiySHFcnjqheUCQVSZPJlDYEGcFe9WTadvxfVBNVXkwdZbcYjoZ5Ut9iLcL0QBvu66NE4zsW1TPcW0uF3aKnInnLwO54NKumbcVDZ00Be79O01zupiOs4X9/B23/VmkqjfOk18fOvpZkwE3mSe8yPfMB6iTFNOM8+RenpMixfOYDNdiz5Bme5nTHWAuNUV3zCffwDRwWeVanRTJxr7F6eb1ONgPDkybJuEKdZmSC1qordM8cZSgs78a4AZFxoZkZHsOLWFMnNLb/+VKhv2z0lnLk5Umpw5NaZCyEz3WBWee9xHfSYv5JdG6QxvIPFE726a8Zsh5ZDE8cXVSwg/Lim8wkhuYwlT23uHq+BPtmm25px4rBRhscnMxIViJFcVckFUlRBETVUT2pSIoiIKqO6klFUhQBUXVUT4oi+RvBap9xpCdxlgAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\" /></p>",
      "OPT4": "<p>\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABMAAAA+CAYAAADJYiAkAAACXElEQVRYR+2VX2hSYRjGf0pUjLEIGiTRBg3U2+mIIijnQGY0MoUVRG05alE3G/iHYl41KpfMEUZFONJFkaUVG9iVsyComLDdqdRFC+ZFESRedBHWsVmBO+I5FcSY3+XhfM/3/OF9H8U34fCPjqIOJtvJVeZZMZdiOh5hYiBKS3SWkHUT2cRDghdGGGsJsBSyohIxQURmgZT/Igu7dWSs12h+fB3dTJiFA/3seT6I5YOHtNdIkzSw8l+5GH36KFuPtaE54cCu/Uys7xBPDj4SmG4XDadKAEXyiRG0XdOYozPcsraizCdwa2+gSYaxqzfKAftCdvI4mvvdZOJ21EooZicxG97gTo9ibBI+SJf5XpC0n5v7HhC3a1FSBn92pKr5JWxxmT8kueDOU7zGLcJvH0m4uzm1+TyhDa94vdfDsL5xBTcRsJ9+fSKwFMCqWidcKjHtxLZoIzjUi7lHj0pE6SqbANkTXr6wVmUqFArJllV20Vr1TLJh0rcGfE350HY4eVtxqe3KHGmHntLEVp6qAZTA2iM6XlRZ0TL22TKzXbOdvKzC4v+CtV/NYVq8x3gyJxBRYXB58Q0dRq9aL2dtl2T6sURaGfdYUDcWyMYuM2i7RNIU/NULkgNY+fTy6u4a20EwI95QMsZJKGdfDx3OZplg+SS+YAOnh3fyuzbKzObPyJRZfEfspJO5o35GjdtQFnOkpiZw3G7Ac/ccRnkBFCmkpzhr7CdcChITrqCbgV6DEIZ4AVfvzT8cUBkB1H6hDlbbo78Yp9rg9QBqe1QPQL5Hdc/qnkl0YI2soO88DblWz93fZwAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\" /></p>",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18439070",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "Data Science and artificial Intelligence",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu8": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tConsider the following statements regarding OLAP (Online Analytical Processing) and OLTP<br />\r\n\t(Online Transaction Processing) in data warehousing:<br />\r\n\t<em>S</em><sub>1</sub> : OLAP is used for decision support and data analysis based on historical data.<br />\r\n\t<em>S</em><sub>2</sub> : OLTP ensures data integrity and consistency across operational systems.<br />\r\n\t<em>S</em><sub>3</sub> : OLAP databases are optimized for fast transaction processing and real-time updates.<br />\r\n\t<em>S</em><sub>4</sub> : OLTP databases are typically denormalized to improve query performance.<br />\r\n\tWhich of the following is/are true?</p>",
      "OPT1": "<p>\r\n\t<em>S</em><sub>1</sub> and <em>S</em><sub>2</sub></p>",
      "OPT2": "<p>\r\n\t<em>S</em><sub>1</sub> and <em>S</em><sub>4</sub></p>",
      "OPT3": "<p>\r\n\t<em>S</em><sub>2</sub> and <em>S</em><sub>3</sub></p>",
      "OPT4": "<p>\r\n\tS1, S2, and S3</p>",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Dsdj/LJX8pBs6q+b96fwiQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Dsdj/LJX8pBs6q+b96fwiQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18439070",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "Data Science and artificial Intelligence",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.66",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu9": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tWhich of the following is a characteristic of OLAP (Online Analytical Processing) systems in data warehousing?</p>",
      "OPT1": "OLAP is designed for high throughput and low-latency transaction processing.",
      "OPT2": "OLAP databases use denormalized data models to improve query performance.",
      "OPT3": "OLAP is used primarily for maintaining current operational data.",
      "OPT4": "OLAP supports complex querying and multidimensional analysis for business intelligence.",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Wkw/v0ACIC+JhZVbmq0HcA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Wkw/v0ACIC+JhZVbmq0HcA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18439070",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "Data Science and artificial Intelligence",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.66",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu10": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tConsider relation R(A, B, C, D, E, F, G) with the following functional dependencies AB \u2192 CD,D \u2192 B, AF \u2192 D, DE \u2192 F, C \u2192 G, F \u2192 E and G \u2192 A. What is the highest normal form?</p>",
      "OPT1": "1NF",
      "OPT2": "2NF",
      "OPT3": "3NF",
      "OPT4": "4NF",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18439070",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "Data Science and artificial Intelligence",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu11": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tWhich of the following statements is/are correct?</p>",
      "OPT1": "Binning without dependence on class labels or predefined threshold is classified as unsupervised discretization.",
      "OPT2": "Discretization by Binning consist of partitioning a continuous attribute into bins of equal width or frequency.",
      "OPT3": "Discretization by histogram analysis uses histogram bins to discretize continuous data based on frequency distribution.",
      "OPT4": "Discretization by histogram analysis always result in bins of equal width.",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "1tsLNxDzUM4tAESa/gW9mQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "1tsLNxDzUM4tAESa/gW9mQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18439070",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "5",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "Data Science and artificial Intelligence",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu12": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tConsider a database where the block size is 1024 Bytes, search key field is 9 bytes and record pointer is 14 Bytes long, block pointer is 7 Bytes, database uses B+ tree for indexing, then order of non-leaf node in B+ tree ________.</p>",
      "OPT1": "64",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "cbJrKHkPIMoqZRj+kuE7Ow==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "5kxMa8YwwyHwJY15nzG3sQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18439070",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "Data Science and artificial Intelligence",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu13": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tWhich of the following statement is/are correct?</p>",
      "OPT1": "<p>\r\n\tIf a relation <em>R</em> is in 3NF and every candidate key is simple then <em>R</em> will be in BCNF.</p>\r\n",
      "OPT2": "<p>\r\n\tIf every attribute is prime attribute in a relation <em>R</em>, then relation <em>R</em> will always be in BCNF.</p>\r\n",
      "OPT3": "Relation with every candidate key is simple, always in 2NF.",
      "OPT4": "<p>\r\n\tRelation <em>R</em> which satisfies 3NF and atmost one compound candidate key is also in BCNF.</p>\r\n",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fUwGNpwrpUE3GIKhfsyzGA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fUwGNpwrpUE3GIKhfsyzGA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18439070",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "5",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "Data Science and artificial Intelligence",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu14": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tThe following key values are inserted into B+ tree in which the order of internal nodes is 4 and that of the leaf node is 5 in the sequence given below. The order of internal node is maximum number of keys in each node and the order of leaf node is the maximum number of pointers that can be stored in it. The B+ tree initially empty.<br />\r\n\t2, 7, 3, 11, 17, 5, 19, 31, 29, 23<br />\r\n\tThe sum of key values which responsible of leaf node split up as a result of these insertion is ________. (Assume right biasing)</p>",
      "OPT1": "71",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "wwB9eMWhKHppCYYezbTsLw==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "5kxMa8YwwyHwJY15nzG3sQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18439070",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "Data Science and artificial Intelligence",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu15": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tConsider a disk block of size 1024 bytes. A block pointer is 6 bytes long. A file has 30000 Employee record of fixed length and each record of size 100 bytes. Assume an unspanned organization is used to store records and SSN takes 9 bytes. Suppose that file is ordered by the key field SSN and sparse primary index is used. The number of block accesses needed to search and retrieve a record from the Employee file, given its SSN value using primary index are ________.</p>",
      "OPT1": "7",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Ar43856SW+87QUodxAaDDw==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "5kxMa8YwwyHwJY15nzG3sQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18439070",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "Data Science and artificial Intelligence",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu16": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tConsider the following statement about hierarchies in data warehouse:</p>\r\n<p>\r\n\tWhich of the above is correct?</p>",
      "OPT1": "A roll-up operation moves from a higher level of to a lower level.",
      "OPT2": "Hierarchies facilitate efficient data navigation and analysis at different aggregation levels.",
      "OPT3": "Star schema do not support hierarchical data structure.",
      "OPT4": "Hierarchical structures can improve query performance in data warehouse.",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "FmRvKjp3/vu5OHwE2HB2FQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "FmRvKjp3/vu5OHwE2HB2FQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18439070",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "5",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "Data Science and artificial Intelligence",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu17": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tConsider a data set with \u201cincome\u201d values as an attribute $ 50000, $ 60000, $ 70000, $ 80000, $ 90000, and $ 98000. To find the min-max normalized value of the \u201cincome\u201d attribute set to $ 98000. If the new range is [0, 4,<br />\r\n\tCalculate the normalized value using the min-max?</p>",
      "OPT1": "4",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "znhkQSpRhMmrD25WN956iw==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "5kxMa8YwwyHwJY15nzG3sQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18439070",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "Data Science and artificial Intelligence",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "TEST_NAME": "Discovered Test 6464885",
  "TEST_ID_ENCODED": "NjQ2NDg4NQ==",
  "TEST_ID": "NjQ2NDg4NQ=="
}